### Marco Ramljak

Date of birth: 21.04.1993

Email: m.l.ramljak@students.uu.nl

#### **PROFILE**

I am a passionate R-user with a B.A. in Political Science and currently pursuing my M.Sc. in Statistics (EMOS Track) at Utrecht University. In my Master Thesis at Statistics Netherlands (CBS), I will be researching the 'Quality of estimates (partly) based on non-probability samples'. In the past, I have worked as a full-time Geospatial Data Analyst at a public sector consultancy implementing advanced quantitative methods and solutions in evaluation designs as well as a research and teaching assistant for topics on Statistics, Data Science and Electoral Studies.

#### **EDUCATION**

09.2019 - 06.2021 M.Sc. Methodologies and Statistics for the Biomedical,

Behavioural and Social Sciences | UTRECHT UNIVERSITY (UU),

The Netherlands

Focus: European Master of Official Statistics (EMOS Track), Inferences from Non-probability Samples

09.2013 - 01.2018

B.A. Politics, Administration and International Relations (Ø1.8) | ZEPPELIN UNIVERSITÄT (ZU), Germany

Focus: Empirical Research Design, (Spatial) Statistics, Regression Discontinuity Design, Election Research

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

02.2020 - 07.2020

#### Practical Teacher | SCHOOL OF ECONOMICS (UU Chair)

Practical teacher for the course 'Applied Data Science and Visualization' within the Bachelor minor 'Applied Data Science'.

02.2018 - 08.2019

## Geospatial Data Analyst | RAMBOLL MANAGEMENT CONSULTING, Germany

Full-time "Professional Year" in the Social and Economic Impact Unit. Conceptualizing and performing impact evaluations of political subsidy programs and strategies with a special focus on geospatial methods. Starting position as "Junior Analyst", promotion to "Geospatial Data Analyst" in December 2018.

10.2017 - 01.2018

#### Internship | INSTITUTE FOR ADVANCED STUDIES, Austria

Analyses on right-wing voting patterns as well as turnout analysis of the Austrian federal elections in 2017 based on electoral geography methods such as geographical-weighted- and ecological-regressions.

09.2016 - 08.2017

## Student Research Assistant & Tutor | METHOD CENTER FOR ECONOMIC, CULTURAL, AND SOCIAL SCIENCE (ZU Chair)

Preparation of courses and exams as well as management of two student survey projects. Tutor for the course "Empirical social research " and "Quantitative methods with R" at B.A. and M.A. level

11.2014 - 10.2015

## Student Research Assistant | EUROPEAN CENTER FOR SUSTAINABILITY RESEARCH (ZU Chair)

Analysis of the effects of blue-green infrastructure on the quality of life in cities. Collecting / analyzing data and creating city profiles for an international research project.

# LANGUAGE SKILLS German Native speaker English Native speaker Croatian

Good command

**Proficient** 

## STATISTICS AND DATA SCIENCE COMPETENCIES

R and R Studio

(5 years) R Shiny	Advanced
Data Visualization	Proficient
Survey Design	Advanced
Spatial Analysis and GIS	Advanced
Counterfactual Analysis	Proficient

#### **WORKING SAMPLES**

R Shiny App visualizing analysis about children day care centers in Germany. Client is the Federal Ministry for Family Affairs, Senior Citizens, Women and Youth:

www.fruehe-

chancen.de/ausbau/betreuungszahlen/

GitHub: www.github.com/R-ramljak

#### **HONORS AND AWARDS**

#### Best Tutor Award 2016

Award from Zeppelin Universität for the best student-evaluated tutorial.

#### Pioneer of the Month 2016

Award from Zeppelin Universität for social commitment.

www.bit.ly/MarcoRamljak

#### Dietrich-Bonhoeffer Award 2013

Award from school management for social commitment.

#### RESEARCH ACTIVITIES

## Summer Institute for Computational Social Science | ETH ZÜRICH, Switzerland

2-week Summer Institute with a focus on learning about and applying methods and tools such as: Machine Learning, NLP, Network Analysis.

## Quantifying Diversity at ZU | ZU EXECUTIVE COMMITEE

A quantitative-spatial analysis to identify student networks to promote the university's diversity. The results were published as an R-Leaflet map and as a project report on ZU Daily: <a href="https://www.bit.ly/ZeppelinGeo">www.bit.ly/ZeppelinGeo</a>

## Student research project | CHAIR OF POLITICAL SOCIOLOGY (ZU Chair)

"Key figures on the municipality level in Germany", development of a panel data set of all local elections in Germany with a descriptive analysis on voting turnout. Preparation for the Bachelor thesis.

## Student research project | THE OPEN GOVERNMENT INSTITUTE (ZU Chair)

"Networking of volunteering - the digital transformation of associations in the field of refugee assistance". The project and the results were presented at DATABUND in Berlin and in a 40-page paper.

#### SOCIAL COMMITTMENT

## Founding member | LEARNING NETWORK, Friedrichshafen

Collaborative network at the ZU for mapping the existing initiatives and identifying gaps for the creation of new initiatives in the field of refugee aid. Practical attempt to introduce the digital transformation into the field of voluntary work.

## Co-Mentoring board member | ROCK YOUR LIFE! FN, Friedrichshafen

In addition to organizing mentoring relationships between students and pupils, I also acted as a mentor for an 8th grader. Furthermore, I have set up a knowledge management system with the project management tool Podio.

## Project coordinator | JUGENDFORUM FN, Friedrichshafen

Development of a political participation platform with 250 young pupils of the city of Friedrichshafen. Leading workshops on open government and new collaboration tools.

## Youth Leader | GLOBAL YOUNG LEADERS CONFERENCE, USA

Scholar and participant in a UN conference simulation in Washington and New York. Participation in workshops and network of hundreds of inspiring young people from around the world.